Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we
have a very dangerous lesson for you guys.
That's right today we're going to talk
about guns or specifically about weapons.
So yeah, we're talking
about kinds of guns.
There are more than I
think I ever knew and we're
going to discuss about
six today but before we
get going, Mark we've got a
phrase in vocabulary preview.
That's right so today
on vocabulary preview
we're going to take a
look at shooting range.
Have you ever been
to one of these places?
Yes, a shooting range.
It's a place like you say
and it's a place where
you can fire your weapons
or you can use guns
safely so you don't kill
anyone or you don't hurt
someone. Now basically
yeah it's a place to
practice shooting.
So maybe for example if you
want to practice how to shoot
guns you go to this
place and they have special
things to help you improve
your shooting abilities.
Usually these are very
very secure. They have
guards and things because you don't want to
give the guns out to anybody. That's right.
But let's listen to today's
dialogue about a shooting
range and find out what
kinds of guns they have.
Hey Nick, what are
you up to? Not much.
Just heading over to the
shooting range. You want to come?
Seriously? You mean
to fire a real weapon?
I don't know man. Yeah it
will be fun. I have a 9mm pistol
that's really easy to
shoot. I also have a revolver
that's really fun too.
They have big targets
at the range that we
could use to practice and
improve your aim.
Yeah that would be cool.
Maybe I can also have a try at
other weapons like a machine
gun or a shotgun. Maybe
even a rocket launcher
or an anti-tank missile or
what about a flamed thrower?
Whoa take it easy there Rambo.
Don't get carried away. These
weapons are not toys and
you must first learn how
to handle them properly.
There are basic rules
that you must abide by in
order to be safe. For example
never handle a weapon
that you haven't
inspected yourself.
Always make sure there isn't
anything in the chamber and never
put your finger to the trigger
unless you are ready to shoot.
Wow I didn't know it always looks so
cool and easy in the movies. The reality is
different you know.
Running and firing a weapon
is a lot harder than in the movies.
So are you ready? Let's do it!
All right we're back so obviously this guy
was very excited about using these weapons
and you may have heard that
we're using this word weapons.
It's basically all
of these things.
I guess anything that can be
used in defense or hurt someone.
Yes anything that
can be used to hurt
someone as a weapon so a knife
can be a weapon not just guns.
Guns are kind of weapon.
That's right so taking a look
at our first type of gun or our
first type of weapon we
have a nine millimeter pistol.
Okay so the weapon
is the pistol and the
pistol is basically a
hand gun but it comes in
different sizes so that's what
the nine millimeter refers to.
That's right that's the size of the projectile
that will come out of the weapon and
a pistol as you say it's
a hand gun it's usually
small and it can fit in
your hand so you can use
just one hand to use this
weapon. Okay so there's
a similar handgun
that's a little bit bigger
that's called a revolver.
That's right a revolver
so this one has a
revolving chamber so you
kind of see this in the
old Western movies when
they have six bullets
right. They like swing their
guns into their side
holsters. Yeah well yeah
that's right the revolver refers to the to
revolve it means to move around to spin.
That's right and so the the
place with the bullet basically
spins after you shoot
the gun. That's right so
that's why it's called
a revolver unlike the
pistol the pistol will
usually not really have a
revolver will have a
magazine. Okay now moving on
to our next type of weapon we
have the very famous machine gun.
That's the one that shoots off really fast
and so basically it's in it's called the
machine gun because
it's it's automatically
releasing all these bullets
at once you just pull the
trigger and many many
many bullets come out.
That's right so in a pistol
or in a revolver usually you
have to press the trigger
and once and it shoots
only once but in the
machine gun you can keep it
pressed and all these
bullets will start flying out.
Very very dangerous very
dangerous okay so now
moving on to the next one
we also took a look at a shotgun.
Okay this is well this is not the biggest
gun we're going to talk about today but
it's a very large gun very
long and you have to use
two hands to hold it.
This is what you usually
use when you go hunting
right. That's right so
as you said it's very
long and it's very loud and
it doesn't really shoot
bullets it shoots little
pellets little cartridges
that are filled with
little rocks for example
and that's what it shoots
and this is why it's
not very precise like like
a machine gun or a handgun
but it does a lot of damage.
Absolutely and what's
something else that
does a lot of damage
our next gun we'll do that.
Well this guy got a little bit excited and
he said he wanted to use a rocket launcher.
Okay so you know what
a rocket is a rocket is
something that's basically
a projectile that goes
into the sky and can it
can basically blow up big
buildings or cars. That's
right and that's what a
rocket launcher is now.
Maybe you've heard of the
word bazooka a bazooka
is a type of rocket launcher.
It's the one it's very
very wide and it's circular
and you usually see it
in movies like Rambo we
talked about where the
Rambo will hold it on one
shoulder it's so big and
the rocket shoots out and
can destroy huge
buildings. That's exactly right
so that's why it's
called a rocket launcher.
Now for our last type of
weapon we have a flame thrower.
Okay well a flame
refers to fire so
fire has flames those
are the the parts that
kind of come up on a
fire the red and orange
and a flame thrower is
a device is a weapon that
will shoot flames not
bullets. Exactly it was
very popular back in
World War II to actually
shoot the flame thrower
into bunkers or into holes
because then you know
this is how you can get
people out of there and
I think flame throwers are
used now to some sort
of degree like to fumigate
sometimes or to burn
weeds when you're in a field.
Right they're not really
used as weapons anymore
although I think I've
seen a number of them in
action movies really
yeah in action movies of
course so we have a
lot of guns a lot well a lot
of different types of
weapons why don't we go
back to the dialogue
let's listen to it again
and we'll be back soon
with Fluency Builder.
Hey Nick what are you up
to? Not much just heading
over to the shooting
range you want to come?
Seriously you mean to
fire a real weapon I don't
know man yeah it will
be fun I have a 9mm pistol
that's really easy to
shoot I also have a revolver
that's really fun too
they have big targets
in the range that we
could use to practice and
improve your aim yeah
that would be cool maybe I
can also have a try at other
weapons like a machine
gun or a shotgun maybe
even a rocket launcher
or an anti-tank missile
or what about a flamed
thrower whoa take it
easy there Rambo don't
get carried away these
weapons are not toys and
you must first learn how
to handle them properly
there are basic rules
that you must abide by in
order to be safe for example
never handle a weapon
that you haven't inspected
yourself always make
sure there isn't anything
in the chamber and never
put your finger to the
trigger unless you are
ready to shoot wow I
didn't know it always looks
so cool and easy in
the movies the reality is
different you know running
and firing a weapon is
a lot harder than in the
movies so are you ready
let's do it all right
we're back so now let's
take a look at our
phrases that we've picked
out for you on fluency
builder fluency builder
so this first phrase comes
from the beginning of
today's dialogue when
Nick is saying well I'm not
doing much I'm just
heading over to the shooting
range that's right so we
know what shooting range
is but when he says
I'm heading over to the
shooting range well this
can be confusing because
to head over has nothing
to do with the head on
your body right it means
I'm going towards some
place I'm going to this
place so it's just another
way of saying going to
right so for example you
can say I'm heading
over to my friend's house
this afternoon that's
right so I'm going to my
friend's house this
afternoon but remember that
this is a pretty relaxed
pretty in formal way of
saying something so you
wouldn't say I'm heading
over to work right say
hey I'm heading over to
his house to hang out
or I'm heading over to the
pizza restaurant to grab
a bite to eat that's right
okay so now obviously
we saw that one of the
guys got very excited
about the idea of using all
these cool weapons
and this friend said whoa
take it easy there Rambo
don't get carried away
I love this phrase this
phrase is something you say
to someone who is maybe
too excited about something
hmm that's right it
means don't go crazy don't
exaggerate right so
maybe at the shooting range
they'll have a revolver
they'll have a pistol
but they're probably
not going to have a rocket
launcher or as he said
an anti tank missile these
are crazy weapons from
movies and so the friend is
saying no you're you're
exaggerating right don't
get carried away now for
example maybe you go to
the mall and you you go
shopping and maybe you
got a little bit carried
away and you spent too
much money that always
happens to me during the
holidays like it carried
away and I buy way too
much stuff that's right
so that's the way that you
would use carried away
and now for our last phrase
he was actually explaining
a couple of rules of
weapon weapon handling
and he said that there are
some rules that he has
to abide by okay so this
is a fixed phrase we
use the the verb to abide
with word like the rules so to abide by
the rules or we must all abide by the rules
this is a fancy way of
saying to follow the rules
or to recognize the
rules and that's right so
you have to abide by
the rules of your school
or maybe you have to
everyone has to abide
by the law right or some
people can say there
are rules in the Bible
that other people abide by
that's right okay so a
lot of great stuff um I
think we've taken a
look at a lot of different
types of weapons and
phrases so pretty interesting
stuff why don't we
listen to it for the last time
hey Nick what are you up
to not much just heading
over to the shooting
range you want to come
seriously you mean to
fire a real weapon I don't
know man yeah it will be
fun I have a nine millimeter
pistol that's really
easy to shoot I also have
a revolver that's really
fun too they have big
targets at the range that
we could use to practice
and improve your aim
yeah that would be cool
maybe I can also have a
try at other weapons like
a machine gun or a
shotgun maybe even a rocket
launcher or an anti-tag
missile or what about
a flame thrower whoa
take it easy there Rambo
don't get carried away
these weapons are not
toys and you must first
learn how to handle them
properly there are basic
rules that you must abide
by in order to be safe
for example never handle
a weapon that you haven't
inspected yourself always
make sure there isn't
anything in the chamber
and never put your
finger to the trigger unless
you are ready to shoot
wow I didn't know it
always looks so cool
and easy in the movies the
reality is different you
know running and firing
a weapon is a lot hotter
than in the movies so
are you ready let's do
it all right we're back
so um talking about
weapons and pistols and all
this has ever used a one
of these have you ever
I have I have been to a
couple shooting ranges
and have fired a couple
of guns I've never fired a
shotgun they don't
usually well sometimes yeah
sometimes they have
but I've shot pistols before
and would you
like it I like it it's an
interesting activity I don't
know how I feel about
using guns on people but
I understand why hunting
is an enjoyable sport
because there is a sport
aspect to it you know
you really have to control
your body and um you're
you can improve you can
get better it's like
darts but with loud guns
and it's very hard to
uh to aim actually to hit
something people think
it's very easy like in the
movies well and I think
it's particularly hard
with handguns yes because
um they're very power
some of them can be very
powerful and so um there's
a kick yeah and you
don't realize it the first time
you shoot a gun and you're
like oh oh that was way
harder than it looks in
the movies I bet you're
a good shot right um
yeah yeah I've always really
enjoyed weapons and uh
my aim is all right although
my my eyesight kind
of I need to use glasses
so it can be a little bit
tricky sometimes especially
when you shoot a
weapon sometimes it's very
you just cleaned it so
it has a lot of oil and
it'll kick out into your
face and get your glasses
wet well that's why we
use goggles at the shooting
range but I'm curious
to know have you guys
ever shot a gun before
have you ever been to
a shooting range our
shooting range is legal
in your country yeah
some places are not yeah
so let us know our
website is EnglishPod.com
all right we'll see you guys there bye